José Ignacio Elzo Merino

Address: Villarrica 1077, Puerto Varas, los lagos, Chile

Mobile: +56 979549717 elzo.merino@gmail.com

Computer Systems Engineering with more than eight years of work experience, my human, academic and vocational training has been focused on the development and implementation of useful proposals in analysis, design, improving internal processes, quality assurance on software products and management projects.

leadership skills to improve performance and camaraderie on QA teams.

I am a positive person, creative, easy to adapt to new work teams, with a strong level of commitment and responsibility to my duties, good interpersonal skills, ability to work in teams under high pressure and goal oriented.

Work Experience

Baufest

QA Architect, Remote

January 2022 to date

Designer of solutions in the quality assurance process of a DevOps team for Lync, Virtual wallet of the bank of Jamaica. Orchestration of the front-end QA team in terms of capacity - Assignment of user's stories and bugs to the team with Azure devOps framework - Approve coverage of automated API's and manual test plans - Documentation with the result of each release; % of successfully cases, failed cases and new issues to be handled in the next sprint. Sanity check between the consistency of users table v/s UI in terms of transactional operations amounts.

Tools

- Android studio: emulator for test Mobile and debugging testing
- webdriverIO typeScript Framework
- appium server for mobile automation
- Postman/karate: GET POST UPDATE to the API Collection
- Postgresql: Consistency between Users and account table VS UI
- Selenium/Python: Creation of automated cases
- Jenkins: For execute Automated Jobs

Comscore

QA Engineer, Santiago, Chile

September 2015 - July 2021

Part of the Agile IT team in VCE and MMX project (validated campaign essentials) reporting system that measures cross platform advertising campaigns in real time, with the purpose of creating competitive strategies to the market. Responsible for verifying the consistency in the API v/s UI reports (Swagger) - Creator and executor of light regressions plans to be executed before the release in order to check health in PRD. - Creator and executor of regressions plans for POST releases verifications - Responsible for creating coverage tickets in JIRA for the automatization team, in order to improve the regression plan.

QA lead Promoted to be the ambassador of VCE project and being the responsible for the quality process - Creator of hot fixes and issues in JIRA to be handled in sprints - Responsible for each monthly release in quality terms, making sure that manual and automated plans were correctly executed - delivering test reports to the IT team - manage capacity for big projects

Education

Gabriela Mistral 2013-2015 IT Engineering degree. - UCINF 2010 - 2013 System Analysis

Languages

Advance, English Speaking and written - Advance, Spanish Speaking and written

Courses and certifications

Scrum Institute Product owner accreditation - Del desarrollo Real Leadership - Coursera Crash course on Python - Coursera API testing with postman

Programing languages

HTML - SQL - JavaScript - Python

Hobbies

Spend quality time with my family and friend - Sports - Movies and tv shows - Reading - Cooking